Meera Vachani

Profile

Digital marketing enthusiast with 5+ years experience. My background includes working for B2C and B2B brands on creative content and digital media execution that drives business results.

Skills

UX Design & Research

Competitive Analysis

Design Documentation

Project Management

Wireframes/Prototypes Social Media, Paid & Organic Usability Testing Digital Strategy & Planning

Design Thinking A/B & Multivariate Testing

Information Architecture Multi-Channel & Inbound Marketing

Design for Accessibility Performance Optimization

Mobile-First & Responsive Design Creative & Content Strategy

Experience

Sr. Social Media Specialist I, Shutterfly Inc. - March 2021 - Present

Other Positions: Online Marketing Specialist April 2019-February 2021, Online Media Marketing Manager (Contract) December 2018-April 2019

Drove in-house paid social awareness strategy across Facebook, Instagram and Pinterest. Improved strategy and process around paid social media tactics, including audience strategy and budget optimization. Streamlined creative development across channels on web and app. Scaled new customer acquisition with strong offers and incentives and by introducing new placements in push, social and email to increase program visibility.

Social Media Manager (Contract), Peak Corporate Network - August 2018-November 2018

Managed 27 company pages, including organic and paid media strategy, while cross-promoting entities. Spearheading blog and video content strategy with external agency partners. Implemented cross-channel campaign tracking to improve campaign measurement. Built and presented quarterly reports to executives. Trained real estate professionals on use cases for social media during monthly lunch & learns.

Digital Media Planner/Buyer, Crossmedia - October 2017-June 2018

Managed 5 client accounts including paid media strategy and execution on social media and search advertising platforms. Built client facing proposals, monthly reports and managed project timelines. Clients included: Tillamook, ZICO®, MINI, Nissin, Kowa Health Care America

Digital Marketing Coordinator, Hornblower Cruises & Events, May 2016-August 2017

Other Positions: Social Media and Content Coordinator April 2015-May 2016,

Digital Marketing Associate January 2015 - March 2015

Strategized and executed full-funnel, cross-channel strategy for 7 national brand entities. Developed brand social media strategy and spearheaded social media page consolidation to maximize brand impact.

Education

University of California, Davis (UC Davis), Davis, CA B.A. Economics, Minor in Communications, 2014